(扉が開く音)
どうぞ 食べてくだ…｡
(ﾁｬｲﾑ)
すみません… 銀時君 いますか？
あの じゃあ
茶菓子だけでも置いていくんで➡
(桂)ごめんくださ～い｡
桂ですけど～｡
ﾁｯ… 留守か｡
事は一刻を争うというのに…｡
Hello!
It's Katsura.
Nobody home? And time is of the essence.
Ex-Excuse me... Is Mr. Gintoki home?
Well, I brought some sweets as a token of... I'll just leave them here then.
Enjoy.
[The Odd Jobs Trio Goes Looking for a Missing Girl. Who is this mystery man, "Daraku"?]
[Gin had too much to drink and has a hangover. It's a little more watery than usual, but...]
["If You're Going to Cosplay, Go All Out"]
(ししおどしの音)
(親父)いや ２～３日
家を空けることはあったんだが➡
Well, it's not unlike her to disappear for two or three days in a row...
１週間ともなると…｡
but she's been missing a whole week.
(親父)連絡は 一切ないし➡
There's been no word from her, and I've asked her friends, but no one knows where she is.
友達に聞いても
誰も知らんときた｡
(新八)…あぁっ
しっかりしてくださいよ｡
Pull yourself together.
だから あんま飲むなって
言ったんすよ｡
That's why I told you not to drink so much.
(親父)親の私が言うのも
なんだが➡
I know it sounds odd for me, her father, to say this,
きれいな娘だから
何か よからぬことに➡
but she's a beautiful girl, so I'm worried she's gotten mixed up in something dreadful.
巻き込まれているのでは
ないかと…｡
(銀時)そうっすねぇ｡
Yes, I agree.
I'd say there's a good chance
なんか こう 巨大な…
ﾊﾑを作る機械とかに➡
she got caught up in some sorta huge ham-processing machine or something.
巻き込まれている可能性が
ありますねぇ｡
No, that's not what I meant. I'm thinking she's caught up in some sort of trouble.
(親父)いえ そういうんじゃなくて
なんか 事件とかに➡
巻き込まれてるんじゃないかと｡
事件？ あぁ ﾊﾑ事件とか？
Trouble? Oh, like ham-processing trouble?
おい たいがいにしろよ｡
Hey, that's enough already. Are trying to ruin this deal?
せっかくきた仕事
ﾊﾟｰにするつもりか？
(ししおどしの音)
But are you sure you want us to handle this?
でも ﾎﾝﾄ
これ ﾎﾞｸらでいいんですかね？
警察に相談したほうが
いいんじゃないですか？
Sounds like a matter for the police.
I can't afford a public scandal.
そんな大事にはできん｡
我が家は 幕府開府以来➡
Our family is of an ancient and honorable lineage
that has served the Tokugawa Family since the time the Shogunate was formed.
徳川家に仕えてきた
由緒正しき家柄｡
娘が 夜な夜な
遊び歩いているなどと➡
The entire clan will be shamed if it gets out that my precious darling
知られたら 一族の恥だ｡
is a club-hopping skank.
(親父)なんとか 内密のうちに
連れ帰ってほしい｡
Please, just bring her back home to me...and keep this quiet.
(ｸﾗﾌﾞのBGM)
(鳥星人)あぁ？
知らねえよ こんな女｡
Huh? Never seen her.
(神楽)この店に遊びにきてた
いうてたよ｡
Someone said she parties here all the time.
(鳥星人)んなこと言われてもね
お嬢ちゃん｡
Maybe that's what someone told you, young lady.
But all Earthlings look alike to me!
地球人の顔なんて
見分けつかねえんだよ｡
(鳥星人)名前とかは？
She got a name?
Um...Ha...Hammy?
(神楽)え～と… ﾊ… ﾊﾑ子｡
ｳｿつくんじゃねえ！
明らかに 今 つけたろ!?
That's a lie! You just made that up.
そんな なげやりな名前
つける親 いるか～!!
Who would give their kid a crappy name like that?!
I forgot her name, okay? It's something like that, I think.
(神楽)忘れたけど そんなん｡
Hey! Are you messing with me?!
(鳥星人)おい～!!
ﾎﾝﾄ 捜す気あんのか!?
Gin, we'll never finish this job if we leave it up to Kagura.
銀さん 神楽ちゃんに任せてたら
永遠に 仕事 終わりませんよ｡
あぁ～ もういいんだよ｡
Yeah, whatever.
どうせ どっかの男の家にでも
転がり込んでんだろ｡ あのﾊﾞｶ娘｡
She's just some slut who's probably camping out some dude's house.
This is retarded.
ｱﾎらしくて やってられっかよ｡
I can't take this job seriously.
ﾊﾑ買って帰りゃ
あのおっさんも ごまかせんだろ｡
Let's buy a big ham and give it to her dad.
He'll never know the difference.
ごまかせるわけねえだろ！
There's no way you could do that!
ｱﾝﾀ どれだけ
ﾊﾑで引っ張るつもりだ!?
And how long are you going to keep milking that ham joke!
あぁ… 悪いけど
二日酔いで 調子悪いんだ｡
Sorry, but I've got a hangover and I feel like crap.
適当にやっといて 新ちゃん｡
Just take care of it, will ya, Shin.
ちょっ… 銀さん！
Wait, Gin!
…あっ すみません｡
Oh, I'm sorry.
(陀絡)小僧…
どこに目つけて 歩いてんだ？
Kid, watch where you're going.
You have the gall to walk around with dust on your shoulder.
肩に ｺﾞﾐなんぞのせて
よく 恥ずかしげもなく 歩けるな｡
少しは 身だしなみに
気を配りやがれ｡
You oughta pay a bit more attention to your appearance.
なんだ？ あの人…｡
Who was that guy?
Shinpachi!
(神楽)新八～｡
もう めんどくさいから
これで ごまかすことにしたよ｡
I'm bo-red!  This fella looks kinda like her.  Let's use him.
どいつもｺｲﾂも
仕事を何だと思ってんだ ﾁｸｼｮｳ｡
Sheesh, nobody is taking this job seriously!
Anyway, there's no way you can pass this guy off as her!
大体 これで
ごまかせるわけないだろ！
ﾊﾑ子じゃなくて ﾊﾑ男じゃねえか！
This isn't even a "Hammy." What you've got here, it's a "Ham-ilton"!
ﾁｯ ﾊﾑなんか どれ食ったって
同じじゃねえか ｸｿが｡
Tsk, eat one ham, you've eaten them all. Shit!
Hah? Going through a rebellious stage?
なに？ 反抗期？ …あっ｡
(神楽)ﾊﾑ男～！
Ham-man!
Hey, don't waste a scene on a minor character!
おい 駄ｷｬﾗが
ﾑﾀﾞに ｼｰﾝ使うんじゃねえよ！
(神楽)ﾊﾑ男 あんなに飲むからよ！
Ham-man, you drank too much.
ｺｲﾂ… 酔っ払ってるんじゃない｡
This dude...he's not drunk.
Okay, never mind, never mind.
(鳥星人)あ～
もう いいから いいから｡
あと ｵﾚやるから
お客さんは あっち行ってて｡
I'll take it from here. You people go away.
(鳥星人)ったく しようがねえなぁ
どいつもｺｲﾂも ｼｬﾌﾞｼｬﾌﾞ ｼｬﾌﾞｼｬﾌﾞ｡
Good grief. Everybody's gone shabu shabu on me, I swear.
Shabu shabu?
ｼｬﾌﾞｼｬﾌﾞ？
ﾊｲﾚｸﾞｱﾙか？
Isn't that that high-leg place?
この辺でなぁ 最近
新種のｸｽﾘが出回ってんの｡
There's a new drug on the streets.
(鳥星人)なんか
相当やばいﾔﾂらしいから➡
Real nasty stuff I hear. Just say no, kids!
お客さんたちも気をつけなよ｡
あぁ～ もう二度と
酒なんて飲まねえ｡
I'm never drinking again.
いやぁ 毎回 言ってるけど
今回は ﾎﾝﾄ ﾏｼﾞで誓うよ｡
I always say that, but this time, I mean it...
誰に誓おう？
Who should I swear to?
お天気おねえさんに誓おう｡
(ﾉｯｸ)
I'll swear to that hot weather girl.
はい 入ってますけど｡
Yes, I'm in here...
≪いつものちょうだい｡
あ？
Give me the usual.
Huh?
≪早く いつものちょうだい って
言ってんじゃん！
I said hurry up and give me the usual stuff!
I can't go on without it!
≪あれがないと ｱﾀｼ もうﾀﾞﾒなの｡
えぇ～…
い… いつものって言われても➡
The...The usual stuff, you say?
いつものより
水っぽいんですけど…｡
It's a little more watery than usual.
Don't jerk me around!
≪なに しらばっくれてんのよ！
I'm not welcome now that I'm broke?!
≪金のないｱﾀｼは
もう お払い箱ってわけ？
Fine, be that way! I'll go to the cops.
≪いいわよ ｱﾝﾀらのこと
警察に たれ込んでやるから！
警察に言う？
ちょ 待てよ お前｡
Huh? Tell the cops? Hold on a minute.
別にいいけど…
何が？ って言われるよ｡
Not that I care...But about what?
Who the hell're you talking to, fool?
(陀絡)誰に話しかけてんだ ﾎﾞｹが｡
I have no use for you anymore, piggy!
もう ﾃﾒｴに 用はねえよ！ ﾌﾞﾀ女!!
(大きな物音)
♪♪～
(部下)なんじゃ？ お前｡
Who the hell are you?
遅いなぁ 銀さん｡
Gin sure is taking long.
どうも 嫌な感じがするんだ
この店｡
I've got a bad feeling about this place...
早く出たほうがいいよ｡
We should leave as soon as we can.
ｱﾀｼ 捜してくるよ｡ …ん？
I'll go find him.
(部下)ﾃﾒｴらか？
ｺｿｺｿ嗅ぎ回ってるﾔﾂらってのは｡
Are you the jerks who've been snooping around here?
な… なんだ ｱﾝﾀら！
Wh-Who are you guys?
(部下)とぼけんじゃねえよ｡
Don't play dumb with us.
最近 ずっと ｵﾚたちのことを
嗅ぎ回ってたじゃねえか｡ あん？
You've been pokin' your noses where they don't belong, haven't cha?
(部下)そんなに知りたきゃ
教えてやるよ➡
If you're so interested in our business, we'll show you
how frightening the Harusame space pirates can be!
宇宙海賊 春雨の恐ろしさをな！
(ﾊﾑ子)う… うぅ…｡
ちょうだい！ あれを早く…！
Give it to me. Hurry!
Hammy!
ﾊﾑ子… 悪かったなぁ おい｡
Sorry about that.
男は男でも お前…➡
Of the all the men to get mixed up with...
you got caught up with the worst of them all.
えらいのに
引っ掛かってたみてえだな｡
Daraku, we've got a weird one here.
(部下)陀絡さん
なんか 妙なのが➡
混ざっちまいましたけど
どうします？
Whatta we do?
(部下)ちょっと 聞いてますか？
Are you listening?
Damn! Can't get it off.
(陀絡)ﾁｸｼｮｳ とれねえ…
どうしてくれんだよ｡
What're you going to do about this?!
おろしたてだぞ この服｡
This jacket is tailored!
How filthy! It's all sticky and won't come off!
汚えなぁ！
ﾍﾞｯﾄﾘついて とれねえよ！
陀絡さんってば
聞いてま… ｵｸﾄﾊﾟｽ!!
Yo, Daraku, are you listening-
(陀絡)身だしなみ整えてるときは
声かけんじゃねえ!!
I told you not to bother me when I'm grooming!
If you've got a problem,
なんか困ったことがあったら➡
just take care of it.
とりあえず
やっときゃいいんだよ｡
Do it snappily and let's go back.
ﾊﾟﾊﾟｯとやって帰るぞ！
There's a rerun of a show I want to watch tonight
夕方から
観てえﾄﾞﾗﾏの再放送があるんだ｡
ｵﾚもだ｡
Me, too...
(陀絡)ｵﾚは 元来 そんなに
人嫌いの激しいﾀﾁじゃねえ｡
I'm not really a violent mysoginist.
だが これだけは許せんというのが
３つ あってな｡
But there are three things I can't abide.
1. People who interfere with my work.
(陀絡)１つめは
仕事のｼﾞｬﾏをするﾔﾂ｡
2. People who don't wash up after using the toilet.
２つめは
便所に入っても 手を洗わんﾔﾂ｡
３つめは 汚らしい天然ﾊﾟｰﾏのﾔﾂだ｡
3. Scuzzy-looking people with naturally wavy hair.
全部…
該当してんじゃねえか～!!
And you're...
...three for three, creep!
I'm honored.
ｿｲﾂは 光栄だ！
ついでに ｵﾚの嫌いなﾔﾂ ３つも
教えてやろうか？
While we're sharing,
how 'bout I tell you the three kinds of people I can't stand?
ひと～つ｡
First!
ぐぉっ！
学園祭準備にはしゃぐ女子！
Girls who get hysterical while preparing for school festivals!
ふた～つ｡
ぐぉっ！
Second!
Totally dumbass guys who take advantage of that and pretend to get all excited about festivals!
それに便乗して 無理に
ﾃﾝｼｮﾝ上げる 愚の骨頂 男子！
み～っつ｡
ぐぅっ…！
Third!
Teachers who smile and condescendingly embrace it all.
それらすべてを包容し
優しくほほえむ教師｡
(部下)ぐぉっ…！
ﾃﾒｴ 要するに➡
In other words,
学園祭が嫌いなだけじゃねえか｡
you hate school festivals, right?
よほど暗い青春おくったな｡
You must've had an unhappy adolescence.
ﾃﾒｴほどじゃねえよ｡
Better than yours.
いい歳こいて 便所で ｽｰﾊﾟｯﾊﾟか？
Aren't you a little old to be sneaking a puff in the john?
(ﾊﾑ子)うぅ…｡
もっとも ﾃﾒｴらが好きなのは➡
Of course, it seems you guys are into some serious poison.
ｼｬﾚになれねえﾊｯﾊﾟみてえだがなぁ｡
天人が来てから 世の中
危ねえもんも増えたからよ｡
Since you Amanto arrived, there've been a lot more dangerous things in the world.
Can't have you pushing drugs on our kids.
困るぜ
若者を たぶらかしてもらっちゃ｡
"Pushing"?
たぶらかす？
Miss Piggy's the one who came running to me.
勝手に飛びついてきたのは
そのﾌﾞﾀだぞ？
望むどおりのもん
用意してやったのに➡
I just gave her what she wanted, but she cried and made a scene.
ｷﾞｬｰｷﾞｬｰ騒がれて
こっちも迷惑してんだ｡
She was causing me trouble.
そうかい｡
ﾊﾞｶ娘が 迷惑かけて 悪かったな｡
I see.
I'm sorry this silly girl caused you trouble.
連れて帰って 説教するわ｡
I'll take her home and give her a good talking to!
Hey, hey. Are you all here to take a leak together?
おいおい…
みんなで仲よく 連れｼｮﾝですか？
便器 足んねえよ｡
There aren't enough toilets.
(部下)ｵﾗ 面倒かけんじゃねえ！
Hey, don't make this difficult.
新八！ 神楽！
おい どうしたんだ!?
Shinpachi! Kagura! Hey! What're they doing?!
ﾃﾒｴら 何しやがった!?
Bastards! What did you do to them?!
(陀絡)お前 目障りだよ｡
…はっ！
You disgust me.
♪♪～
ぐっ!!
あぁ～～っ!!
また汚れちまったよ｡
Dirty again. It's definitely ruined now.
ﾀﾞﾒだ こりゃ｡ 新しいの買おう｡
I'll just have to buy a new one.
♪♪～
ふんばれ… おい！
Hang in there!
絶対 死なせねえから｡
I won't let you die on me.
ｵﾚが 必ず 助けてやるからよ｡
I'll get you through this, you'll see!
Get rid of it. Dump him.
(髑髏)捨てちまえよ そんなもん｡
He ain't gonna make it, anyway.
(髑髏)どうせ ｿｲﾂは助からねえ｡
ﾃﾒｴには 誰かを守るなんて
できっこねえんだ｡
You don't have what it takes to rescue anyone.
今まで 一度だって 大切なもんを
守りきれたことがあったか？
When have you ever managed to protect anything that really matters?
目の前の敵を
斬って斬って 斬りまくって➡
All you do is lash out at whatever's in front of you.
それで 何が残った？
You slew them all, and what did that leave you?
(髑髏)ただの死体の山じゃねえか｡
Nothing but a mountain of corpses.
ﾃﾒｴは 無力だ｡
You're powerless.
Just throw it all away. Take the easy road.
もう 全部 捨てて
楽になっちまえよ｡
お前に守れるものなんて
何もねえんだよ!!
There's nothing you can protect!
…はっ！
(ふすまが開く音)
It's unlike you to be having a nightmare.
(桂)ｶﾞﾗにもなく
うなされていたようだな｡
昔の夢でも見たか？
Dreaming about the past?
ﾂﾞﾗ？ なんで ﾃﾒｴが…｡
Zura? What the hell are you doing here?
そうだ！ うっ… ううっ…！
I remember now!
無理はせぬがいい｡
Better not strain yourself.
左腕は 使えぬうえ
肋骨も 何本かいっているそうだ｡
You can't use your left arm, and I'm told you've broken several ribs.
むこうは もっと重症だ｡
The other person is even worse.
お前が かばったおかげで
外傷は そうでもないが➡
She looks okay on the outside. You broke her fall.
体中が ｸｽﾘに むしばまれている｡
But her entire body has been ravaged by drugs.
(桂)処置が早かったのは
不幸中の幸いだが➡
She was lucky that she was treated quickly, but it's unclear whether she'll recover.
はたして 回復するかどうか…｡
あの ｸｿｶﾞｷめ…！
Stupid kid...
But what were you doing in a dive like that?
というか 貴様は なんで
あんなところにいたんだ？
というか なんで お前に
助けられてんだ ｵﾚは…｡
Never mind that, how did you manage to save me?
というか
この前のこと謝れ この野郎｡
Apologize for last time, you bastard.
というか お前は
これを知っているか？
Speaking of which...
...are you familiar with this?
最近 巷で出回っている
転生郷と呼ばれる 非合法薬物だ｡
It's an illegal drug called "Paradise" that's been going around lately.
(桂)辺境の星にだけ咲く
植物から作られ 依存性も強い｡
It's made from a flower that grows only on a remote planet.
It's very addictive.
(桂)使用した者は 皆 例外なく
悲惨な末路を たどっている｡
And everyone who uses it without exception, meets a tragic end.
天人がもたらした この悪魔を
根絶やしにすべく➡
The Anti-Amanto party is working on digging out this evil by its roots.
我々 攘夷党も
情報を集めていたんだ…｡
So we're gathering information on it.
(桂)そこに お前が
降ってきたらしい｡
That's apparently where you fell into all of this.
(桂)ｵﾚの仲間が見つけなかったら
どうなっていたことか…｡
Who knows what would have happened to you if my men hadn't found you.
というか お前は なんで
あんなところにいたんだ？
But what were you doing in a dive like that?
というか ｱｲﾂらは
いったい 何なんだ？
More importantly, who were those guys?
宇宙海賊 春雨｡
The Harusame space pirates.
銀河系で 最大の規模を誇る
犯罪ｼﾝｼﾞｹｰﾄだ｡
They're the largest organized crime syndicate in the Milky Way.
Their main source of income is profits from the sale of illegal drugs.
(桂)ﾔﾂらの主だった収入源は
非合法薬物の売買による利益｡
The very tips of their tentacles have reached Earth.
(桂)その触手が 末端とはいえ
地球にも及んでいるというわけだ｡
天人に侵された 幕府の
警察機構など あてにできん｡
We can't rely on the government police. They're totally corrupted by the Amanto.
我らの手で どうにかしようと
思っていたのだが➡
We hoped we could do something on our own.
貴様が それほど
追い詰められるくらいだ…➡
They were able to corner even you.
They seem to be a very formidable adversary.
よほどの強敵らしい…｡
時期尚早かもしれんな｡
We might be acting prematurely.
おい 聞いてるのか！
Hey.
Are you listening?
仲間が さらわれた｡
ほっとくわけにはいかねえ｡
They kidnapped my friends. I can't afford to rest and bide my time.
その体で 勝てる相手と…？
You think you can beat them in your condition?
｢人の一生は 重き荷を負うて
遠き道を 往くが如し｣｡
"A man's life is like traveling a long road with a load on his shoulders."
昔なぁ 徳川田 信秀という
おっさんが言っていた言葉でな｡
A long time ago, an old man named Nobuhide Tokugawa said that...
誰だ その ﾐｯｸｽ大名！
家康公だ 家康公！
Learn your history, retard! It was Lord Ieyasu. Lord Ieyasu!
最初に聞いたときは➡
The first time I heard that, I thought, what a lame thing to say,
なにを辛気くせえことを…
なんて思ったが➡
なかなかどうして➡
but what do you know, that old guy had a point.
年寄りの言うこたぁ
ﾊﾞｶにできねえな…｡
It's not really a burden.
荷物ってんじゃねえが➡
誰でも 両手に
大事に 何か抱えてるもんだ｡
Everyone's got both hands full of something that matters.
だが 担いでるときにゃ
気づきやしねえ…｡
You just don't realize it when you're carrying it.
その重さに気づくのは 全部
手もとから 滑り落ちたときだ｡
It's only after it slips out of your hands that you realize how heavy it was in the first place.
もう こんなもん持たねえと
何度 思ったかしれねえ｡
So many times, I thought I'd never carry a load like that ever again.
なのに また いつのまにか
背負い込んでんだ…｡
And yet,
before I realized it, I was carrying it again.
いっそ捨てちまえば
楽になれるんだろうが➡
I'd feel so much better if I just got rid of it.
But I just can't bring myself to do it.
どうにも そういう気になれねえ｡
ｱｲﾂらがいねえと 歩いてても➡
Without those guys, just walking around isn't fun anymore.
あんまり おもしろく
なくなっちまったからよ…｡
しかたあるまい｡ お前には
池田屋での借りがあるからな｡
I guess there's no point in arguing.
I still owe you a favor from Ikedaya.
いくぞ｡
あ？
Let's go.
片腕では 荷物など持てまいよ｡
You can't carry that load with just one hand.
今からｵﾚが お前の左腕だ｡
Starting now, I'm your left arm.
《ここは どこだろう…？
Where is this place?
What am I doing right now?
ﾎﾞｸは今 何やってるんだ…？》
Are these the ones who were snooping around?
(ｶｴﾙ星人)ｺﾔﾂらが
主たちの周りを➡
嗅ぎ回っていた連中かｹﾛ？
えぇ｡
Yeah.
(陀絡)最近 少々
こうるさくなってきたんで➡
They were becoming a bit of a nuisance, so we set a trap.
They fell right into it.
網張ってたら
簡単に かかりましてね｡
(陀絡)大方 天人嫌いの
攘夷派の連中でしょう｡
They are most likely rebels who hate the Amanto.
ｹﾛｹﾞ～ﾛ｡
Ribbit. Ribbit.
There was one other odd samurai,
(陀絡)もう１人
妙な侍がいましたが➡
but we got rid of him together with a loud-mouthed customer.
そっちのほうは
騒いだ客と一緒に 始末しました｡
あまり ﾊﾃﾞに動くなと言ったｹﾛ｡
I told you not to attract too much attention.
こっちも
幕府の連中を押さえ込み➡
There's a limit to how much we can keep the government officials
under control and have them look the other way.
見て見ぬﾌﾘをするにも
限界があるｹﾛ｡
えぇ わかってますよ｡
Yes, I understand.
We are only able to do business thanks to your magnanimity, my lord.
自由に商売できるのも
旦那のおかげですからね｡
して ｺﾔﾂらの始末は どうつける？
So, how're you going to dispose of these two?
(陀絡)拠点を聞き出して
つぶしますよ｡
I'll get the location of their headquarters out of them, and destroy it.
(陀絡)これ以上 仕事のｼﾞｬﾏは
されたくないんでね｡
I don't want them interfering any further with our work.
首謀者は おそらく
あの 桂とかいう男だｹﾛ｡
The leader is probably that man named Katsura.
They're mad dogs that have even bared their teeth at the government.
ﾔﾂらは 我ら幕府にまで
牙をむく狂犬ゆえ 侮るなｹﾛ｡
Don't take them lightly.
(ﾄﾞｱが開く音)
Daraku, a moment please?
(部下)陀絡さん ちょっと…｡
(部下)表に 妙なﾔﾂらが
来てまして…｡
There are some weirdos outside.
妙なﾔﾂら？
Weirdos?
You handle it. I'm busy right now.
適当に 処理しとけ｡
ｵﾚは今 忙しいんだ｡
I'm telling you again...we don't need any of your crap!
(部下)だ～から ｳﾁは
そういうのいらねえんだって！
つれねえな｡
ｵﾚたちも 海賊になりてえんだよ｡
Aw c'mon.
We want to become pirates, too.
Take us with you.
連れていってくれよ～｡
なぁ？ ﾂﾞﾗ｡
Ain't that right, Zura?
ﾂﾞﾗじゃない｡ ｷｬﾌﾟﾃﾝ ｶﾂ～ﾗだ｡
It's not Zura. It's Captain Katsura.
ｵﾚたち 幼い頃から➡
Ever since we were little punk kids, we've dreamed of becoming pirates.
海賊になるのを夢みていた
わんぱく坊主でさ～｡
失われた秘宝 ﾜﾝﾊﾟｰｸというのを
探してんだ！ なっ？ ﾂﾞﾗ｡
We wanna search for the lost treasure: "One Park."
Right, Zura?
ﾂﾞﾗじゃない｡ ｷｬﾌﾟﾃﾝ ｶﾂ～ﾗだ｡
It's not Zura. It's Captain Katsura.
知らねえよ｡ 勝手に探せ｡
Never heard of it. Go find it yourselves.
んなこと言うなよ～｡
ｵﾚ 手がﾌｯｸなんだよ｡
Don't be like that. My hand's a hook.
もう 海賊かﾊﾝｶﾞｰに
なるしかねえんだよ｡
I can only be a pirate or coat hanger.
Whatever. You go be whatever you want to be.
知らねえよ！
なんにでもなれるさ お前なら｡
(部下)とにかく帰れ｡
ｳﾁは そんなに甘いところじゃ…｡
Anyway, go home
This isn't a job fair.
面接くらい 受けさせてくれよ～｡
At least give us an interview.
ほ～ら 履歴書もあるぞ｡
See, we even brought our resumes.
わっ！
(部下)お～い 起きたか？ 坊主｡
Hey, are you awake, kid?
(部下)おねむの時間は
おしまいだよ！
Sleepy time's over!
(部下)まったく こんな若いのに
海賊に捕まっちゃうなんて➡
You're so young. Such a shame you got captured by pirates!
かわいそうにねぇ｡
あぁ そうなんだ…｡
Oh, that's right...
ﾎﾞｸ 海賊に捕まったんだ…｡ あっ！
I've been captured by pirates.
神楽ちゃん!!
Kagura!
(陀絡)おじさんはねぇ➡
I hate filthy scum who interfere with my business.
不潔なﾔﾂと 仕事のｼﾞｬﾏをするﾔﾂが
大っ嫌いなんだ｡
もう ここらで ｼﾞｬﾏなﾈｽﾞﾐを
一掃したい｡
So now I want to clean out you pesky rats.
お前らの巣を教えろ｡
Tell me where your nest is.
If you try to hold out, she dies.
意地張るってんなら ｺｲﾂは死ぬぞ｡
なんの話だよ!!
とぼけんな｡
What're you talking about?!
Don't play dumb. We know you're a rebel.
ﾃﾒｴが 攘夷志士だってのは
わかっている｡
はっ!? くっ…！
Tell us where your secret base of operations is!
(部下)ﾃﾒｴらのｱｼﾞﾄ
教えろって言ってんだよ！
(部下)桂の野郎は どこにいんだ!!
Where is that scum Katsura?!
うわっ！
なに言ってんだよ お前ら!!
What're you guys talking about?!
ﾎﾞｸらは
攘夷志士なんかじゃないし➡
We're not exclusionist rebels, nor do we know where Katsura is!
桂さんの居場所なんて知らない!!
Let Kagura go! This is the land of the samurai!
神楽ちゃんを離せ!!
ここは 侍の国だぞ!!
お前たちなんか 出ていけ!!
You guys get out!
侍だ？ そんなもん
もう この国にゃいねえ！
Samurai, you say? There's no such thing in this country.
ほわちゃ～!!
うごっ…！
Kagura!
神楽ちゃん!!
Don't want to get in your way.
足手まといになるのは ごめんよ｡
ﾊﾞｲﾊﾞｲ｡
Bye-bye.
待てぇ～!!
Wait!
Wait! Wait! Wait! Wait! Wait! Wait!
待て待て待て待て待て 待て～!!
はひふへ ほ～っ!!
♪♪～
ｲﾃﾃﾃ…｡ 傷口 開いちゃったよ｡
Oww... My wound opened up.
あのぅ 面接会場は ここですか？
Uh... Is this where the interview is being held?
こんにちは～｡ 坂田 銀時で～す｡
Hello, I'm Gintoki Sakata. I'd like to try out for captain.
ｷｬﾌﾟﾃﾝ志望してま～す｡
趣味は 糖分摂取｡ 特技は➡
My hobby is eating sugar.
My special talent is being able to sleep with my eyes open.
目 開けたまま眠れることです｡
(神楽/新八)銀さん！
Gin!
You little bastard...still alive, eh?
ﾃﾒｴ 生きてやがったのか!?
(爆発音)
(陀絡)なんだ!?
What the?!
Daraku! There was an explosion in the storeroom!
(部下)陀絡さん！ 倉庫で爆発が!!
(部下)転生郷が…!!
The Paradises!
(桂)ｵﾚの用は終わったぞ！
My work here is done.
あとは お前の番だ 銀時！
好きに暴れるがいい!!
You're up, Gintoki!
Go ahead and trash the place to your heart's content.
ｼﾞｬﾏするﾔﾂは ｵﾚが除こう！
I'll take care of anybody who gets in your way.
ﾃﾒｴは 桂…!!
You're...Katsura!
No!
違う！ ｵﾚは ｷｬﾌﾟﾃﾝ ｶﾂ～ﾗだ!!
I'm Captain Katsura!
(爆発音)
(部下)桂だ～！ やれ～っ!!
It's Katsura! Get him!
Off with Katsura's head!
桂の首をとれ～!!
You're finished now, bastards.
ﾃﾒｴら 終わったな｡
完全に 春雨を敵に回したぞ｡
You've made an enemy of the entire Harusame gang!
(陀絡)今に 宇宙中に散らばる
春雨が➡
Soon, Harusame from throughout the universe will come to kill you.
ﾃﾒｴらを 殺しにくるだろう｡
Yeah? So What? You won't be around to see it.
知るかよ｡ 終わんのは ﾃﾒｴだ！
いいか？ ﾃﾒｴらが 宇宙のどこで
何しようとかまわねえ｡
Listen... I don't care what you do somewhere else in the universe,
だが ｵﾚの この剣
ｺｲﾂが届く範囲は…➡
but anywhere within reach of my sword,
ｵﾚの国だ！
is my country!
不粋に入ってきて
ｵﾚのもんに触れるﾔﾂは…➡
Anyone who comes here and messes with my people
将軍だろうが 宇宙海賊だろうが
隕石だろうが…➡
whether he's the Shogun, space pirates, a meteorite...
ぶった斬る!!
I'll cut 'em all down!
♪♪～
ﾌｯ｡ おい…｡
You know...
ﾃﾒｴ…
便所で 手ぇ洗わねえわりに➡
Bastard...you may not wash your hands in the bathroom,
結構 きれいじゃねえか…｡
but you're pretty clean.
♪♪～
あぁ ﾀﾞﾒっすね…｡
ﾎﾝﾄ ﾌﾗﾌﾗして歩けない｡
Hoo, I'm beat. Everything's spinning. I can't even walk straight.
日 浴びすぎて ｸﾗｸﾗするよ…｡
おんぶ｡
I'm dizzy from too much sun.
Carry me.
なに甘えてんだ 腐れｶﾞｷども！
What're you complaining for, you little brats!
誰が いちばん疲れてっか
わかってんのか！
Do you know who's the most exhausted?!
二日酔いのうえに 体中ﾎﾞﾛﾎﾞﾛでも
頑張ったんだよ 銀さん!!
I fought my way over here even though my body is a mess and I have a hangover!
ﾎﾞｸらだって
頭が ﾌﾗﾌﾗなんですからね…｡
Both of us are woozy, too, you know!
そうｱﾙよ！ ﾌﾞﾗﾌﾞﾗｱﾙよ！
That's right! Boozy!
つきあってらんねえ｡
ｵﾚは 先 帰るからな！
I can't stand you guys. I'm going on home.
♪♪～
Come on, knock it off already!
いいかげんにしろよ ｺﾗ～ｯ!!
Okay! Fine! You want me to carry you, I'll carry you! Your wish is my command!
上等だ！
おんぶでも何でもしてやらぁ～!!
(神楽と新八の笑い声)
What a miraculous recovery! Damn you!
元気爆発～じゃねえか ｵﾒｴら｡
(神楽)銀ちゃん 私
ﾗｰﾒﾝ食べたくなってきたよ｡
Gin, I feel like eating ramen.
ﾎﾞｸ 寿司でいいですよ｡
Sushi for me.
ﾊﾞｶ野郎｡ 誕生日以外に
そんなもん食えると思うなよ！
Stupid! You don't get that except on your birthday.
ったくよ… 重てえな ﾁｸｼｮｳ｡
Man... You guys are heavy, dammit.
(桂)ﾌﾝ｡ 今度は せいぜい
しっかり つかんでおくことだな｡
Now that you've got them back, hold on tight.
♪♪～
Kimiko... Kimiko!
I'm so glad you're safe! Kimiko!
Hey, old man, wrong one!
I know how it is, pops. There are some things you never want people to see.
No, it's like this because he can see those things.
(親父)公子～！ 公子～!!
無事で 何よりじゃ～！ 公子～!!
おい ｺﾗ じじい｡
どこ見てんだよ！
わかるぞ 親父｡ 人間 誰だって
見たくねえもんはある｡
いや 見えてるから
こうなってるんじゃ…｡
(親父)公子～！ 公子～!!
(ししおどしの音)
[Preview]
This is Gintoki.
The other day, I was chasing after a stray cat that stole my fish, naked.
Everyone under the sun, even a little dog, was laughing.
Anyway, the next episode:
Three episodes including "Men Have ... *snip*
["You Only Gotta Wash Under Your Armpits - Just the Armpits", "Rough cooking style for men"]
[Next time, we have 3 episodes like XXX-san. The revival of family-style animation?]
It's not Zura. It's Captain Katsuuura, believe it!
Did I mess up the punchline?
ﾂﾞﾗじゃない｡ ｷｬﾌﾟﾃﾝ ｶﾂ～ﾗ
だってばよ～！ ｽﾍﾞった…｡